Let's start with gathering.
دعونا نبدأ بجمع البيانات.
Data acquisition can happen in a variety of ways.
يمكن الحصول على البيانات بعدة طرق مختلفة.
In this case, you already acquired
في هذه الحالة، حصلتم بالفعل
the data by downloading some files that were available.
على البيانات عن طريق تحميل بعض الملفات المتاحة.
In other cases, you might need to get the data from an API or scrape it from a web page.
في حالات أخرى، ربما تحتاجون إلى الحصول على البيانات من واجهة برمجة التطبيقات أو استخلاصها من صفحة ويب.
In many companies, they might have
في العديد من الشركات، قد يكون لديها
an existing database from which you can pull data and answer questions.
قاعدة بيانات حالية يمكنكم سحب البيانات منها والإجابة عن الأسئلة.
You'll also often need to combine data from multiple different formats.
ستحتاجون في كثير من الأحيان إلى دمج بيانات من عدة تنسيقات مختلفة.
It's okay if some of these terms are unfamiliar to you,
لا بأس إذا كانت بعض هذه المصطلحات غير مألوفة لكم،
they'll be covered in more depth in our data
ستُغطى بمزيد من التفصيل في دورتنا التدريبية
wrangling course which is linked in the instructor notes.
الخاصة بتعارض البيانات والتي تجدها في ملاحظات المعلم.
The lesson on gathering data within that course is great if you'd
الدرس الخاص بجمع البيانات في تلك الدورة التدريبة رائع
like to learn more about how to get data from a variety of sources.
إذا كنت ترغب في تعلم المزيد عن كيفية الحصول على المعلومات من مصادر مختلفة.
Your files are in a format called CSV which stands for a comma separated values.
ملفاتك بصيغة تسمى CSV التي ترمز إلى قيم مفصولة بفاصلة.
A CSV file is a text file.
ملف CSV عبارة عن ملف نصي.
It's similar to a spreadsheet in terms of its tabular structure.
إنه يشبه جدول البيانات من حيث هيكله الجدولي.
But if you've ever seen IF statements or other functions in your spreadsheets,
ولكن إذا كنتم قد رأيتم عبارات IF أو الدوال الأخرى في جداول البيانات،
this isn't possible in CSV files.
فهذا مستحيل في ملفات CSV.
They hold only the raw data.
إنها تحتوي فقط على البيانات الأولية.
The contents of a CSV file are also very easy to process manually using code.
تُعالج محتويات ملف CSV يدويًا بسهولة جدا باستخدام الكود.
Unlike for example, an XLSX file,
بخلاف ذلك مثلًا، ملف XLSX،
which is the format used by Microsoft Excel.
هو التنسيق الذي يستخدمه Microsoft Excel.
Let's take a look at one of your files which contains cancer data.
لنلق نظرة على الملفات التي تحتوي على بيانات السرطان.
Here's what the file looks like in Google Spreadsheets.
إليكم ما يبدو ملف في جداول بيانات Google.
There's a row for each time a tumor was
يوجد صف لكل مرة يزال فيها ورم
extracted and columns for different pieces of information,
وأعمدة للمعلومات المختلفة،
such as the ID, diagnosis,
على سبيل المثال الهوية والتشخيص
radius, texture, area, and smoothness.
ونصف القطر والملمس والمنطقة والنعومة.
Now, here's what the file looks like if you open it in a plain text editor.
الآن، هكذا يبدو الملف إذا قمتم بفتحه في محرر نصي عادي.
A text editor is a program like Notepad,
المحرر النصي هو برنامج مثل Notepad،
Sublime or Adam, that shows exactly what's present in the file.
Sublime أو Adam، يُظهر بالضبط ما الذي يوجد في الملف.
As you can see, the actual content of the file are very simple.
كما ترون، المحتوي الفعلي للملف بسيط للغاية.
The header row from the spreadsheet is present as the first line of the CSV file.
يظهر صف الرأس من جدول البيانات كالسطر الأول في ملف CSV.
The second row of the spreadsheet is the second line of the CSV file and so on.
والصف الثاني لجدول البيانات هو الصف الثاني في ملف CSV وهكذا.
Within each row, you'll see the first cell followed by a comma,
في كل صف، سترون الخلية الأولى متبوعة بفاصلة،
followed by the second cell,
تليها الخلية الثانية،
followed by a comma and so on.
متبوعة بفاصلة وهكذا.
This makes CSVs very easy to process in programming languages like Python
مما يجعل ملفات CSVs سهلة المعالجة للغاية بلغات البرمجة مثل Python
and packages such as Pandas have specific functions for loading data from CSVs.
كما أن الحزم مثل Pandas لها دوال محددة لتحميل البيانات من ملفات CSVs.